P.D. Browne papers, Inclusive: 1860-1986, Bulk: 1950-1986
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Research Interests, 1860 (copy) -1985, undated; 3
  - Thomas J. Pilgrim, 1962-1978; 7
    This subseries contains source materials used by Browne for his included essay on Thomas J. Pilgrim, early Texas Baptist educator. The essay is included as Essay, "Thomas J. Pilgrim."
    - Correspondence, 1963 January-March (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1963 June-1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Printed Materials, 1936-1978, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Essay, "Thomas J. Pilgrim": (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Essay, "Thomas J. Pilgrim": (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Photographs, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Negatives, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Henry Lee Graves, 1956-1962, undated; 8
    This subseries contains source materials used by Browne for his included essays on Henry Lee Graves, first president of Baylor University at Independence. Browne's research interests in Fairfield, Texas, and Baylor University coalesced in Henry Lee Graves, who served as Baylor president and later became president of Fairfield Female College.
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essay, "Dr. Henry Lee Graves and Family": (1 of 3), 1960 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essay, "Dr. Henry Lee Graves and Family": (2 of 3), 1960 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Essay, "Dr. Henry Lee Graves and Family": (3 of 3), 1960 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Essay, "Henry Lee Graves at Fairfield": (1 of 2), 1956 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Essay, "Henry Lee Graves at Fairfield": (2 of 2), 1956 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Printed Materials, 1926-1976, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Notes: (1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Notes: (2 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Photographs, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - W.L. Moody, 1962-1965, undated; 9
    This subseries contains source materials used by Browne for his included essay on W.L. Moody's Company G, 7th Texas Infantry. As part of Gregg's Brigade, much of the regiment was surrendered at Fort Donelson, but the regiment received enough recruits to continue as a regiment. The unit fought at Chickamauga and then joined Cleburne's division for the Atlanta and 1864 Tennessee Campaigns. The Battle of Franklin, Tennessee, in 1864, destroyed the 7th Texas as an effective fighting force. Remnants of the unit surrendered as part of Joseph Johnston's army in the Carolinas in 1865.
    - Essay, "W.L. Moody's Company G": (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Essay, "W.L. Moody's Company G": (2 of 2), 1962 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Notes, 1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)